S-Sakamoto...
Where...
Where are you?
Sakamoto...
Sakamoto!
Why do you always leave me?
I'm anxious.
Did you abandon me?
I'm always being left alone.
I'm scared.
I'm hurt, so I'm left out?
Where are you?
You're just going to ignore me?
Why won't you tell me anything?!
Why does this have to...
Like with the chips.
...happen to me?
I didn't mean to not tell you.
I was just doing my job.
You've got things you've...
Life's just a rat race.
...been keeping from me, don't you?
It's kill or be killed.
You have three chips, don't you?
No one would believe it...
That's all there is to it.
I should make these chips...
He's just using me.
...my trump card!
What are they doing here?
I want to go home.
No!
Let me go home.
If I don't, I'll die.
I miss them.
I don't want to die!
I miss them!
Daddy.
Wh-Who's there?
Is someone...
Is someone there?
Are you back, Sakamoto?
Daddy.
What?
That almost sounded like...
I've finally gone—
Daddy.
Y-Yuzuhiko!
What are you doing here?!
When did you arrive on this island?
I can't—
I missed you so much.
Why haven't you come home yet?
I-I couldn't...
I miss you.
I know...
but I'm badly hurt.
And I don't have enough chips yet.
I miss you!
I miss you, too.
Of course I do!
But the chips...
I don't have eight chips.
Sure you do.
Akiko!
Is your mind so far gone that you can't count?
Count?
How many chips do you have?
H-How many chips...
One, two...
Three...
That isn't enough, is it?
No, I have more.
Four, five, six...
Seven...
Eight!
I-I can...
I can go home!
Just wait for me, Yuzuhiko, Akiko!
Daddy's coming! He's coming home!
And then we can all go get
something good to eat.
Let's all go to Ajinoya and have all the okonomiyaki we can eat!
akaku somatta rashinban
A compass stained red
me no mae ni hirogaru
Extends before my eyes
I defy the beating of my heart
oboreteiku dead heat
Drowning in dead heat
mujun ni michita itami de
Suffering from pain full of contradictions
inochi tashikameru you ni
As if to make sure I'm alive
I’m left to lick my wounds again
Real hodoiteiku
Uncovering the reality
kurikaeshi miru kodoku ni otsu hitokage
I keep seeing people succumbing to loneliness
ibitsu na yume
A twisted dream
Destroy my existence now
ima kudakechitta sekai no naka de
The world has shattered into pieces
jijoujibaku kirisuteteiku
I must break free of my own machination
konna yuuwaku ni ubaware
Lured by the temptations
Disillusion delusion
itsuka ushinatta azayaka na hibi mo
I lost sight of the bright days at some point
subete wo wasureta toki ni
But once I've forgotten everything
Resolution redemption
asu mo tatakau sube nigirishimete
Get hold of a way to keep fighting tomorrow
So take hold
Just watch a new world
as it will unfold
Don’t let go
of your vision
Just take life head on
and find your reason
Bonds
It's gotten foggy.
The sun's starting to set, too.
The lizards will be waking up soon.
Let's hurry back.
What's wrong?
Shh.
I hear something...
I-It isn't a lizard, is it?
No, this sound...
It can't be...
A homing type?
Ryouta!
It's locked onto me!
Ryouta, run!
This is bad.
If it gets within range, it'll detonate!
Homing type bombs...
The only person with this type of BIM...
It can't be!
Mr. Taira!
If you're the one doing this, stop!
We're on the same side!
Ryouta, behind you!
No!
It's within range!
Got him!
Ryouta!
He got my leg.
Th-This is really bad.
Mr. Taira, please stop!
Why are you doing something so awful?
Why are you doing this?
Why...
When you get six chips,
the two of you will be tested.
Is Mr. Taira betraying us to get all the chips?
No response.
Where is he?
Where's that damned old man hiding?!
Why?
Why did he betray us?
We promised to get out of here together,
but still he... Why?!
I wondered if maybe you wouldn't come back,
If you had abandoned me...
It was all I could think about.
No!
No, no, no, no, no!
This time, it's over.
If you leave me here, I... I...
won't be able to stay sane.
We need clean towels and water for you.
Don't worry.
We'll come back with some delicious food.
Is it my fault?
No matter what my reasons were,
I'm the one who made him feel so anxious.
He was so terrified.
Why did I never take notice?
Was I...
Was I doing...
the same thing my dad did?
My dad was obsessed with work and never spent any time with me.
And my mom divorced and remarried without giving one god damn for me.
"Adults are selfish.
They only think about themselves.
They're satisfied with pretending to care about me."
That was what I thought.
In spite of that, have I treated Mr. Taira exactly in the way I once was?
Was I pretending not to see how he felt?
That's right.
You were running away from reality.
Ryouta...
Ryouta!
Snap out of it!
I hear another BIM.
Quickly!
We need to get out of here.
Ryouta!
Run, Himiko!
What are you doing?
Hurry and run!
If the game we're playing has the same rules as BTOOOM!...
then that homing type works just like it does in the game.
I know what I've got to do.
I know what I...
Himiko!
Wh-What?
I knew it.
It only explodes when it comes within range of its target.
I'll protect him.
I'll protect Ryouta!
Th-This...
Could it be...
There's no doubt.
Himiko...
She's the same Himiko I met in BTOOOM!.
Mr. Taira isn't moving.
But he's out there, somewhere we can't see him.
Himiko...
It's okay.
The homing types can only lock on to a single person.
I'll take care of them.
A-All right.
I'm sorry.
Sakamoto, Himiko...
Don't hate me for this.
You know...
It's a game, right?
Isn't that right?
Ain't that right, Yuzuhiko?
Akiko?
It's coming!
Where?
I can hear it.
Over there.
It doesn't matter how many you send!
There's something wrong here.
If he really intended to kill me,
would he waste his BIMs like this?
No, he wouldn't.
He's smarter than that.
That means that BIM is targeted at...
Mr. Taira's target is...
you, Himiko!
I did it.
I outsmarted him.
H-He outsmarted me!
D-Damn...
Damn!
Mr. Taira...
C-Crap.
Mr. Taira! Mr. Taira!
Oh no...
He's going to kill me.
Stay away!
Mr. Taira!
Stop this, and come back to us!
Ryouta...
Ryouta!
M-My hip...
Mr. Taira!
They're going to kill me.
I only have one left?
Before he can kill me... I must kill him!
To get back to Yuzuhiko!
To get back to Akiko!
Mr. Taira,
where are you?
Mr. Taira, I want to apologize to you.
I want to...
I want to go back with you!
To go home with you.
I won't worry you again.
I'll do things right this time.
Please, just give me one more chance!
Please, Mr. Taira.
Please let me apologize, Mr. Taira.
Mr. Taira!
S-Sakamoto, I...
I... I...
This is karma, isn't it?
Punishment for what I did.
Sorry, Sakamoto, Himiko.
I just wanted to go home.
I missed my family.
That was all.
Yuzuhiko... Akiko...
I'm sorry.
Daddy can't take any more pain.
Mr. Taira?
Why?
Why did this happen?
Weren't we going to go home together?
Stand up.
Say something!
Tell me another stupid joke, like you always do!
Start eating your instant ramen before it's cooked!
I never got... to apologize to you.
Why?
Why?!
Do you think Mr. Taira planned to betray us the whole time,
the way Date did?
No, he wasn't like that.
He was just a normal person.
And that's why he got scared and suspicious.
No one wants to die.
Everyone wants to go home.
So, when he got hurt and was alone with despair closing in...
his heart broke.
I...
I basically killed him!
Do you want to go home, too?
Yeah, I want out of here,
away from this hell.
You can leave, Ryouta.
I can leave?
Yes.
I took these chips from back there.
One of them is Mr. Taira's.
He took the other two without telling us.
With these and the three we found, it makes six.
Plus one from me
and one from you.
Those are the eight you need to leave the island.
If one of us dies, one can leave.
So that's why you should kill me.
Yes.
This is the way it should be.
I don't have anywhere to go back to.
I didn't have a place to belong, but you changed me.
I feel like even if we weren't connected in the real world, our hearts were.
Although it was in a virtual world,
you saved me.
You also saved me on this island,
all those times when I almost died,
and when I almost fell apart.
So now I understand.
You are my hope for survival.
Ryouta...
If you can be saved...
If it means you can live...
No matter what becomes of me...
I won't mind.
D-Don't be stupid!
You think I want to go home
so much that I'd sacrifice you?
Do you think that's the kind of guy I am?
I won't abandon you!
I wouldn't ever do that.
Not in this world or the virtual one!
Himiko, you're my Himiko, aren't you?
I finally realized it.
I finally got to see you.
Himiko...
I always...
I always wanted to meet you.
Himiko?
That's right.
She's still scared.
She should be scared.
But for me, she's doing her best not to be.
But I...
Not going to do it?
Remember what I told you?
The first one to move wins.
Show her what a man you are.
Or are you still satisfied with holding yourself back?
Sh-Shut up!
You'll never catch up to me that way.
Shut up!
I don't...
look up to you anymore!
I finally understand.
What matters is caring for others.
If I'd known that...
I wouldn't have let Mr. Taira die.
I could've gotten along with my family.
I thought I was the only one that mattered.
I looked down on others.
If I hadn't, I never would've been brought to this island!
Oda...
I'm not like you.
I won't be like you.
Stop invading my thoughts!
Ryouta?
Is something wrong?
Sorry for springing this on you,
but doing this here, in the heat of the moment...
It's not right.
Himiko, let's leave this island together.
Let's go back together!
And then...
I'll start dating you officially.
All the way from the farthest ends of the world
saihate no story idaite
I have been wandering without a destination
ate mo naku samayoitsuzuketa
Yes.
Now a new world emerges from the haze
nijinda new world
This is what's right.
I will escape this hell... together with Himiko.
The game has only just begun
The beginning of the end is in my eyes
ima hajimari no eyes
This is where tomorrow brings a new game
It's time to learn that pain is gain
Ready fight
24 hours...
Get things back online in 24 hours!
Once you get to the island, begin at once.
Got it?
Understood.
Goodbye.
To squash my past despair
kako no shitsubou nuritsubusu tame ni
Make sure the clients don't find out about this.
I've had to sacrifice my future
gisei ni shite kita mirai
Y-Yes, sir.
Until my life expires
boku no life ga tsukiru made
To have technical issues on the island now, of all times...
I'll keep fighting my fate
sono sadame buchikowashiteiku no sa
Ah, step out and find your evolution
Of all the times...!
Projecting my own world
hitori no sekai wo utsushite
I'm caught between the fake and the real
genjitsu to fake no hazama de
Ryouta, I'm sorry.
With only one chance to reset my life
ichido dake reset yurushite
This is all I can do.
I'm sure I'll find salvation inside my heart
sukui wa kitto kokoro no naka ni
All the way from the farthest ends of the world
saihate no story idaite
I have been wandering without a destination
ate mo naku samayoitsuzuketa
Now a new world emerges from the haze
nijinda new world
The game has only just begun
the game has only just begun
The beginning of the end is in my eyes
ima hajimari no eyes